THOMAS JUDE RAKESH KENNEDY

thomasjk10@gmail.com ● 8553982712 ● Bangalore

SENIOR ANALYST

Skilled and motivated software engineer with 5+ years of experience in mainframe development, testing and operations, looking to explore opportunities and challenges in this field. Interested in contributing my skills and learn from others so as to grow intellectually as well as within an organization.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Attention to detail in mainframe operations tasks
- Quick understanding of new concepts
- Providing value innovative tools

- Providing team support/encouragement and trainings
- Due diligence and compliance
- Taking quick action on requests

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

CAPGEMINI 2017 - present

Analyst- AXA Technologies

• Providing Mainframe support for production jobs (which are the primary aspects of banking transactions and insurance applications) by handling abends effectively and in a timely manner by using tools such as:

OPC -> for batch monitoring and resolving abends (space/contention/MQ/JCL)

Omegamon -> for monitoring CICS statuses along with other alerts

MQ Series -> for monitoring Queue statuses

HMC ->for performing IPL, reset clear activities

SILVA -> for monitoring and taking action on abend notifications

- Immediate and appropriate action on WTORs and critical alerts on consoles
- Reducing redundant abends by providing suggestions to application teams to provide permanent fixes
- Performing shutdown and IPL of LPARs on request as well as part of weekend activities
- Supporting release activities, which included monitoring and releasing of applications on request
- Handling requests such as planning applications, restarting jobs, deleting dependencies, manual hold/release/mark completion on jobs/applications
- Providing PPM tickets to application teams to take action on abends not in scope
- Following up on batch run and online down and up time
- Using IMS to bring UP/DOWN transactions on request
- Handling queue failures by altering trigger depth parameters in error and datagram queue
- Checking subsystems statuses on NETVIEW and taking action if in problem status by checking VOTE using INGLIST command and also starting/stopping subsystems on request
- Updating of process related documents to share with clients and team so as to maintain standard work procedure
- Developed automation tools ->Used VBA to help keep track of the files accessed on Production Mainframe environment and another tool to effectively track the SLA of SILVA tickets worked on by every team member
- Received appreciation from clients as well as got awarded with 'Rising Star' certificate in recognition
 of my dedication and efforts in the process

CAPGEMINI (erstwhile IGATE)

2014 - 2016

Software Engineer - MUFG Union Bank

- Improved client recognition of offshore team members by providing on-time deliverables in coding/testing tasks
- Received multiple appreciation mails for well-documented test results
- Developed new and effective tools using REXX which benefitted clients as well as offshore team in validating codes
- Volunteered to provide extra support/validation during implementation of Cobol/JCL codes into production environment
- Lead by example and motivated colleagues by taking up challenging coding tasks myself, in JCL/COBOL and completing them with accuracy
- Focused on maintaining high standard documentation of any testing before and after implementation phases to keep errors/bugs down to a minimum
- Secured multiple certificates for sincere work in helping enhance the automation(VBA and JCL) of certain processes within the team(one automation includes auto-email triggering of mainframe job failures)

CAPGEMINI (erstwhile IGATE)

2013 - 2014

Systems Associate - Royal Bank of Canada (RBC)

- Learned and implemented the use of multiple features within mainframes like ENDEVOR, ICETOOL
- Prepared extensive and well-structured test result documentations after rigorous testing
- Actively participated in providing solutions/suggestions for code changes within COBOL/JCL's which helped in staying on track of pre-defined delivery timelines

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Internship at Continental Automotive Components (India) Pvt. Ltd

2012

- Learned industrial processes Cluster (in automobiles) manufacturing, PCB designing and machine designing
- Expressed interest in learning industrial software's like CAD
- Developed and presented a new innovative idea for a particular PCB manufacturing section for the industrial work floor which would be cost effective

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

- Enjoyed teaching Math, Science and English to students at Shanti Bhavan before and at the start of my professional career.
- Actively participated in IGATE's 'Project Akshara' initiative to elevate the education at government schools by distributing books to students and conducting workshops.

TECHNOLOGY SKILLS

• MS Word, Excel(VBA included), Power point, Windows OS, Visual Basics, Java

- Android Basics (self-taught from online courses at Udacity)
- Python Basics (self-taught from online courses at Coursera, Udacity and obtained certificates as well)
 working on mini projects with assistance from an external mentor

EDUCATION/ PERSONAL DETAILS

Bachelor of Science, St. Josephs College Primary and Secondary School, Shanti Bhavan

2010-2013 1997-2010

- DOB: 28-01-1992
- Hobbies: Reading, self-learning to work with of various software's/ programming languages like Adobe Premier Pro, Movizu(animation software), excel macros, android, python, java script
- Nationality: Indian

DECLARATION:

I, Thomas Jude Rakesh Kennedy, hereby declare that the above stated details are true to the best of my knowledge.